SHIVANI ANAND

Unit #703, Rathburn Rd. West Mississauga, ON, L5B 0K6 https://www.linkedin.com/in/shivani-anand-4b58781a3/

C: 437-996-1296 shivaniii.anand@mail.utoronto.ca

Objective

Second year Computer Science student at the University of Toronto, Mississauga seeking an internship at. I'd like to work on my critical thinking, technical and interpersonal skills and garner more experience.

Summary

Self-motivated and hardworking student demonstrating creative and analytical ability with a passion for programming in :

- C#, Python, Java, HTML, C, MySQL

Experienced with creating desktop and console games and applications, Overseen the creative process along with teammates inC#, Python and Java for school work and as side projects.

Works well with technology and has knowledge about various software applications:

- **O/S:** Windows 11/10/8/7; Linux
- **Applications:** OpenOffice; MS Word, Excel and Access; Sketchbook; Paint.NET; Ubuntu; Google Drive

Experience with software skills:

Problem-Solving Skills; Product Enhancement; Agile Scrum Team;
Project Management; Research; Data Structures;
Computer Architecture

Experience with Artistic skills:

- Drawing (with pencils, crayons, stylus), Painting

Education and Training

Honours Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Major, Communication, Culture, Information & Technology Major University of Toronto | Mississauga, ON Sept. 2020 - Present

• Relevant Course: Software Design; Software Tools & Systems Programming; Computer Organization;

Father Michael Goetz Secondary School | Mississauga, ON Dec. 2016 - June 2020

Graduated with Goetz Club

Work Experience

Bell Canada - Technical Analyst

May. 2022 - Aug. 2022

- Aided in the analysis of Bell's store support
- Created reports and rundowns using Excel and Visio
- Developed and presented business case in a group

CGI - Junior Developer Sept. 2022 - Dec. 2022

• Inspected deployed javascript code for a client website

Additional

UTMSAM - UofT (2020 -)

• **2022:** Part of the events team. Helped in organizing events by creating slide decks, and promoting the events.

CSSU - UofT (2020 -)

• **2021:** By being one of the Orientation leaders, I Interacted with incoming first-years and helped them navigate through the CSSU orientation. Played games online to break the ice and helped them by answering doubts about university life, distance learning and joining clubs

Econ Canada Research Projects - UofT (2020-)

• **Sept 2021 - Jan 2022:** Part of a large group of students who work under research assistants. The role is to collect data from colonial data about trade relations and traded products between assigned years from official documents and organize the information obtained into excel sheets. Part of quality assurance.

Web-Development Side project - UofT (2020 -)

• **2022** - Part of a group chat consisting of 3 other members working towards building a website with a database application dedicated to making budgeting easier for students. The website is being built using HTML/CSS, React and MySQL.

Father Michael Goetz Secondary school

- Computer Science (2018 2020)
 - Participated in coding events out of school
 - Hosted multiple coding events at school with teammates
 - Learnt new programming languages
 - Won a Silver Medal at the Skills Canada 2020
- Math Club (2017 2020)
 - Participated in multiple math contests outside of school
- Prom Committee (2019-2020)
 - Event planning and Designed invitations for prom